Inventory of the Jay Johns Papers 1918-1974
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Papers of Lee-Jackson, Inc., 1859-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 3:1-22)
  - Material concerning Robert E. Lee and the Lee family, 1778-1894, n.d. (Box-folder 3:19-22)
    - Material concerning the Lee Family, 1778-1894, n.d., 22 items. Cys of ALsS. (Box-folder 3:22)
      - Cha[rle]s Carter, Shirley, [Charles City County, Virginia], to Henry Lee, esquire, n.p., 20 May 1793., 2 pages. XCy of ads. (Box-folder 3:22)
        Gives consent for Henry Lee to marry his daughter.
      - C[arter] C. Lee, Richmond, [Virginia], to "cousin Nat," Nat[haniel] Burwell, Staunton, Virginia, 1 February 1848., 3 pages. XCy of ads. (Box-folder 3:22)
        Much family news; discusses farming and corn crops; wedding of cousin Ann Wickham's son.
      - C[arter] C. Lee, Richmond, [Virginia], to "Nat," Nat[haniel] Burwell, Roanoke County, Virginia, 25 June [18]48., 3 pages. XCy of ads. (Box-folder 3:22)
        Much family and friend news.
      - M[ary] C[ustis] Lee, Baltimore, [Maryland], to Abbey Louise Peters [Cook], [Saratoga, New York], 22 August [1850]., 2 pages. XCy of ads. Including TCy of ads. 1 page. (Box-folder 3:22)
        Her son Custis is in his first year at West Point; give news of various engagements and weddings; inquires about matrimonial prospects; family news.
      - Alfred Lee, Wilmington, Delaware, to N[athaniel] Burwell, n.p., 10 February [18]52., 1 page. XCy of ads. (Box-folder 3:22)
        Discussing pricing of Dr. Butler's book The Life of the Apostle Peter.
      - William Henry Fitzhugh Lee, Baltimore, [Maryland], to "Brother" [George Washington Custis Lee], n.p., 15 February 1852., 2 pages. XCy of ads. Including TCy of ads. 2 pages. (Box-folder 3:22)
        Inquires about his grades; Uncle Smith is to go to sea and take command of the Princeton; talks of going to college; describes a grand ball that took place; family news.
      - G[eorge] Washington C[ustis] Lee, Jackson, Mississippi, to Lt. Genl. Pemberton[?], n.p., 26 December 1862., 1 page. XCy of ANS. (Box-folder 3:22)
        Referring another note to Lt. Genl. Pemberton for his appropriate action.
      - M[ary] Custis Lee, New York, New York [?], to Abby [Louise Peters] Cook, Richmond, Virginia [?], [ca. 27 January 1865]., 1 page. XCy of ads. Including TCy of ads. 1 page. (Box-folder 3:22)
        Talks about the "millenary line" of work; a great number of weddings and parties going on.
      - Mary (Custis) Lee, "Derwent," Virginia, to Miss Emily Mason, n.p., September 1865., 1 page. TCy of L. (Box-folder 3:22)
        General Lee accepts Lexington position to teach; grieves over situation the southern people are living through.
      - Mary Custis Lee, Lexington, [Virginia], to [?], 16 September 1873., 1 page. XCy of ads. (Box-folder 3:22)
        Expresses gratitude for others' consideration and memory of her husband, General Robert E. Lee.
      - H[enry] Lee, n.p., to Mrs. Fendall, n.p., 6 May [18]86., 2 pages. XCy of ads. (Box-folder 3:22)
        Expresses appreciation for her "maternal tendency" talks of being under a doctor's care.
      - H[enry] Lee, [Philadelphia, Pennsylvania], to R. S. Garnett, Congress, Washington, D.C., 21 January, 1894., 3 pages. Xcy of ads. (Box-folder 3:22)
        Discusses writing an article for the papers concerning landowners and tariffs.
      - [?, Baltimore, Maryland], to George W[ashington] Custis Lee, West Point, New York, [ca. 15 February?]., 2 pages. TCy of AL. Including XCy of AL. 2 pages. (Box-folder 3:22)
        Talks about "fast" Baltimore girls; many people sick with meazles [sic]; family news.
      - Charlotte W. Lee, cousin, Arlington, [Virginia], to Nat[haniel] Burwell, Staunton, Virginia, 30 April [?]., 2 pages. XCy of ads. (Box-folder 3:22)
        Thanks him for the gift of apples; mentions Lucy Carter's, a cousin, wedding; family news.
      - M[ary] C[ustis] Lee, n.p., to C. D. Walker, n.p., n.d., 1 page. XCy of ads. (Box-folder 3:22)
        Enclosing money for her son [George Washington] Custis Lee and herself.
      - Alfred Lee, n.p., to N[athaniel] Burwell, Jr., n.p., n.d., 1 page. XCy of ads. (Box-folder 3:22)
        Thanks for the check and encloses a receipt.
  - Correspondence and information about Ezekial Moses., 31 items. (Box-folder 3:23)
  Series 4: Virginia Trust for Historical Preservation
- Virginia Trust for Historical Preservation, 1967-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 4:1-14)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 4:1-3)
    - General Correspondence, 1967-1971., 19 items. (Box-folder 4:1)
    - General Correspondence, 1972-1974., 78 items. (Box-folder 4:2)
    - General Correspondence, n.d., 11 items. (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Business Papers., 26 items. (Box-folder 4:4-5)
    - Financial Papers and Taxes., 16 items. (Box-folder 4:4)
    - Legal Papers., 10 items. (Box-folder 4:5)
  - Miscellaneous Papers., 10 items. (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Papers concerning the Lee-Fendall House, 1970-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 4:7-14)
    - Correspondence concerning the Lee-Fendall House, 1970-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 4:7-11)
      - Correspondence, 1970-1971., 19 items. (Box-folder 4:7)
      - Correspondence, 1972., 153 items. (Box-folder 4:8)
      - Correspondence, 1973., 139 items. (Box-folder 4:9)
      - Correspondence, 1974., 101 items. (Box-folder 4:10)
      - Correspondence, n.d., 3 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
    - Business Papers: Financial and Legal Items., 6 items. (Box-folder 4:12)
    - Photograph., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
    - Printed material about, miscellaneous histories, maps, etc., 29 items. (Box-folder 4:14)
  Series 5:Miscellaneous Papers
- Miscellaneous Papers, 1774-1971, n.d. (Box-folder 4:15-21)
  - Newspaper Clippings concerning Jay W. Johns., 40 items. Ncls. (Box-folder 4:15)
  - Newspaper articles by James Kilpatrick., 82 items. (Box-folder 4:16)
  - Newspaper clippings., 36 items. (Box-folder 4:17)
  - Photographs identified with Mr. and/or Mrs. Johns., 13 items. (Box-folder 4:18)
  - Photographs., 33 items. (Box-folder 4:19)
  - Preservation Interests including material on Fort Necessity, Pennsylvania; Prestwould Farm; and dealers catalogues., 19 items. (Box-folder 4:20)
  - Printed material, 1774-1971, n.d., 19 items. (Box-folder 4:21)
    Including a ticket to the 1936 Democratic National Convention; a history of the city of Alexandria, 1774-1783; an autobiographical sketch of Anthony-Charles Cazenove; 1971 Roster of the Cincinnati; Virginia Municipal Review; and Annual Report, 1958, of Charlottesville Woolen Mills.
  Series 6:Miscellaneous Interests
- Miscellaneous Interests 1928-1954, n.d. (Box-folder 4:22-28)
  - Biographical Information on Claudius Crozet., 2 items. (Box-folder 4:22)
  - Chief Justice John Marshall's watch., 36 items. (Box-folder 4:23)
  - United Daughters of the Confederacy, Breckinridge Chapter. 1928-1954, n.d. (Box-folder 4:24-27)
    - Application Forms., 28 items. (Box-folder 4:24)
      Items are arranged alphabetically.
    - Correspondence, 1928-1954, n.d., 6 items. (Box-folder 4:25)
    - Business Papers, 1928-1954, n.d., 50 items. (Box-folder 4:26)
    - Miscellaneous materials, including a brief history of the chapter, program schedules, newspaper clippings, and pamphlets., 30 items. (Box-folder 4:27)
  - Miscellaneous materials., 22 items. (Box-folder 4:28)
    These materials include the American Foundation for the Blind, an address delivered to the graduating class at Staunton Military Academy by Jay Johns [?], receipts, poems, a print, and lists of names.
  Series 7: Ash Lawn
- Ash Lawn, 1930-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 5:1-11)
  - Correspondence, 1930-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 5:1-7)
    - Correspondence, 1930-1974., 72 items. (Box-folder 5:1)
    - Correspondence concerning the Buildings and Grounds., 30 items. (Box-folder 5:2)
    - Correspondence concerning the Buildings and Grounds., 26 items. (Box-folder 5:3)
      Items, including photographs and printed material, deal primarily with the Statue of James Monroe.
    - Correspondence concerning Employment., 27 items. (Box-folder 5:4)
    - Correspondence concerning Furniture, including photographs., 64 items. (Box-folder 5:5)
    - Correspondence concerning the History of Ash Lawn., 42 items. (Box-folder 5:6)
    - Correspondence concerning L. G. Hoss and the rental of Monroe items., 94 items. (Box-folder 5:7)
  - Business Papers., 69 items. (Box-folder 5:8)
  - Photographs., 45 items. (Box-folder 5:9)
  - Printed Material., 46 items. (Box-folder 5:10)
  - Miscellaneous Material., 10 items. (Box-folder 5:11)
  - James Monroe Material. James Monroe Material., 10 items. (Box-folder 5:12-18)
    - Correspondence. (Box-folder 5:12-16)
      - Correspondence concerning the birthplace of James Monroe., 14 items. (Box-folder 5:12)
      - Correspondence concerning the bust of James Monroe., 24 items. (Box-folder 5:13)
      - Correspondence concerning celebrations in honor of James Monroe., 4 items. (Box-folder 5:14)
      - Correspondence with dealers, collectors, etc., 131 items. (Box-folder 5:15)
      - Correspondence concerning the family bible of James Monroe., 11 items. (Box-folder 5:16)
    - Miscellaneous Material., 22 items. (Box-folder 5:17)
    - Printed Material., 36 items. (Box-folder 5:18)
  Series 8: Manuscript Collection
- Manuscript Collection (Box-folder 6:1-7)
  - Manuscripts, 1789-1891, n.d. (Box-folder 6:1-5)
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by persons last name.
    - Brooks, Phillips, 2 October 1891., 1 item. 1 page. ads. (Box-folder 6:1)
      Phillips Brooks, Boston, [Massachusetts], to " Gen[era]l Secretary," n.p. Agrees to deliver an address at the opening service of the Church Congress.
    - Custis, George Washington Parke, 1854, n.d., 4 items. (Box-folder 6:2)
      - George Washington Parke Custis, Arlington House, [Virginia], to Benson J. Lossing, Poughkeepsie, New York, 19 June 1854., 3 pages. ads. Including Xcy. 4 pages. (Box-folder 6:2)
        Is recovering slowly, but still depressed; has begun painting as much as possible; tells of his "Surrender of York Town" as still hanging in the Rotunda of the Capitol, and being well received; the horses were particularly noted; describes his newest project, including "Trenton," and his use of original profiles by Sharpless [?] in drawing "the Chief" [George Washington]; comments on an article published in the Home Journal concerning mysterious truths connected with General Washington; is pleased at being considered for designing the tomb of [General Washington ?]; gives facts about the President's March, "Hail Columbia."
      - Description of Arlington Spring by [George Washington Parke Custis], n.d., 1 page. Ams. Including XCy. 1 page. (Box-folder 6:2)
    - Gallatin, Albert, 1789-1846, n.d., 25 items. (Box-folder 6:3)
      - Albert Gallatin, Springhill, to Ephraim Douglas, Uniontown, 18 November 1789., 3 pages. ads. Including XCy. 2 pages. (Box-folder 6:3)
        Discussion of possible legal action to be taken against Daniel Weibel, a carpenter living on Gallatin's plantation, who owes a sum of £30-40 to him.
      - Check for $160.00 made payable to William and John Wister, 18 December 1800., 1 page. XCy of ADS. (Box-folder 6:3)
        Signed by Albert Gallatin.
      - Receipt for $100.00 from Albin Mellier for furniture from Gallatin's home on Friendship Hill, Fayette C[ourt] H[ouse], Pennsylvania, 2 July 1832., 1 page. ADS. Including XCy. 1 page. (Box-folder 6:3)
      - Albert Gallatin, New York, [New York], to A[lbin] Mellier, Rockland near Baltimore, Maryland, 1 July 1832., 1 page. ads. In French. Including XCy and translation. 2 pages. (Box-folder 6:3)
        Financial transactions discussed, including mention of the Bank of the United States; matters concerned with Friendship Hill.
      - Albert Gallatin, Astoria, to [John Russell] Bartlett, Astor house, [New York, New York], 10 September 1846., 1 page. ads. Including XCy. 1 page. (Box-folder 6:3)
        Health has improved, but change in weather is adversely affecting him; returns Dr.[] Dickinson's specimens; wishes he could personally become acquainted with him [Dr. Dickinson].
      - Miscellaneous related material, n.d. (Box-folder 6:3)
        These items include a souvenir booklet about Friendship Hill, Fayette County, Pennsylvania; map showing Gallatin property; and correspondence between Jay Johns and others concerning the possible purchase of Friendship Hill.
    - Hill, D. H., 13 October 1868., 1 item. 1 page. ads. (Box-folder 6:4)
      D. H. Hill, Office of "The Land We Love," Charlotte, North Carolina, to Henry R. Howeland, n.p. Reports that [?] Johnston is in Europe, but that W[illia]m Johnston in Baltimore, [Maryland], should be able to supply the requested information.
    - Lee, William, 5 December 1817., 1 item. 2 pages. ads. (Box-folder 6:5)
      W[illia]m Lee, Treasury Department, Washington, [D.C.], to Col. [?] Symmes, Collector, Alexandria [Washington], D.C. Report of three cases of furniture (parts of curtains, footstools, fire screens) belonging in the President's house, having arrived from Havre on board the ship Atlas.
  - Xeroxed copies of autographed/signed Includes letters, 1778-1889, n.d., 16 items. (Box-folder 6:6)
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by correspondents last name.
    - Adams, Louisa Catherine, 26 November 1820., 2 pages. XCy of ads. Including XCy of a portrait. 1 page. (Box-folder 6:6)
      L[ouisa] C[atherine] A[dams], Washington, [D.C.], to [?]. Expresses "mortification" at the refusal of a friend, Eliza [Monroe?] to visit her because of the unfinished state of her home.
    - Andrews, C. W., 10 December [18?]51[?]., 1 page. XCy of ads. (Box-folder 6:6)
      C. W. Andrews, Shep[?], to [?]. Information given about the construction of a symbol representing the 13 states, to be built with wood.
    - Beauregard, G. T., 23 May 1873., 1 page. Typescript. (Box-folder 6:6)
      G. T. Beauregard, New Orleans, [Louisiana], to W[illia]m B[ur?]well, Sec[retar]y and Treas[uerer] [of the] Chamber of Commerce, New Orleans, [Louisiana]. In regards to a circular sent from the Savannah, [Georgia], Chamber of Commerce relative to a proposed canal through the southern states, connecting the Mississippi River to the Atlantic Ocean.
    - Burwell, Thomas N., 12 June 1810., 2 pages. XCy of ads. (Box-folder 6:6)
      Tho[ma]s N. Burwell, Fincastle, [Botetourt County, Virginia], to [?]. Mainly business letter discussing the transportation and accounting of a crop of hemp; his sister had a baby girl, and is fine.
    - Cabell, Mayo, 6 March 1845., 1 page. XCy of ads. (Box-folder 6:6)
      Mayo Cabell, Union Hill, to Nathaniel Burwell, n.p. Business letter informing him that the amount of $150.00 due for his horse has been credited to his account at the Farmer's Bank.
    - Early, Jubal A., 29 September 1874., 4 pages. XCy of ads. (Box-folder 6:6)
      J[ubal] A. Early, Lynchburg, [Virginia], to Gen[era]l A. R. Lawton, Savannah, Georgia. Questions figures given by [Joseph E.] Johnston in his recent book about the Civil War concerning the Battle of Richmond in 1862.
    - Fitzhugh, William, 16 December 1778., 1 page. XCy of DS. (Box-folder 6:6)
      Receipt signed by William Fitzhugh for money received from the Treasurer [of the Continental Congress?] as allowance for the October Session [in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania].
    - Kemper, James L., 1874-1889., 2 items. (Box-folder 6:6)
      - J[ames] L. Kemper, Richmond, [Virginia], to Colonel John S. Mosby, n.p., 2 July 1874., 1 page. XCy of ads. (Box-folder 6:6)
        Sends all of their correspondence for the past year that he could find.
      - James L. Kemper, near Orange C[ourt] H[ouse], Orange County, Virginia, to General Henry M. Cist, n.p., 24 May 1889., 1 page. XCy of ads. (Box-folder 6:6)
        Would like to have a copy of the reprint of General Boynton's Includes letters concerning the Battles of Chattanooga and Chickamanga; tells of the death of General Robert Emmet Rodes of the Army of Northern Virginia, 19 September 1864.
    - Meade, W., n.d., 3 pages. XCy of ads. (Box-folder 6:6)
      W. Meade, Millwood, to Nathaniel Burwell, Baltimore, Maryland Gives instructions for him to follow upon his [Burwell] arrival in Washington, [D.C.] involving Bishop Lee and Dr. Butler; family news.
    - Pope, John, 23 September 1864., 1 page. Typescript. Including ads. (Box-folder 6:6)
      Jo[h]n Pope, Head-Quarters, Department of the Northwest, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, to Maj. Gen[era]l P. H. Sheridan, U.S.A., n.p. Congratulations upon Sheridan's recent victory [at Opequon?]. Including ads., 4 August 1965, from Edward T. Downer, Cleveland, Ohio, to Jay [Johns], n.p., commenting on the Pope item.
    - Smead, A., 15 August 1862., 1 page. XCy of ads. (Box-folder 6:6)
      A. Smead, A[ssistant] I[nspector] G[eneral], H[ea]d Q[ua]r[ter]s, V.D. to Maj. Gen[era]l Ewell, [?] Division. Relays message from Gen[era]l [Thomas Jonathan] Jackson to have cavalry remain where it is.
    - Trimble, I. R., n.d., 1 page. Typescript. (Box-folder 6:6)
      I. R. Trimble, Manassas, [Virginia], to Gen[era]l[?], n.p. Reports the capture of Manassas, and his loss of men.
    - Tunstall, Samuel William, 25 December 1847., 3 pages. XCy of ads. (Box-folder 6:6)
      S[amuel] W[illia]m Tunstall[?], n.p. to Nathaniel Burwell, Western Asylum, Staunton, Virginia. Tells of dinner at a neighbor's home, and of Mr. and Mr. Gilmer also being guests; suggests that he not return home yet.
    - Washington, George, 5 August 1798., 1 page. XCy of ads. (Box-folder 6:6)
      G[eorge] Washington, Mount Vernon, [Virginia], to Ja[me]s Marshall, n.p. Is in need of a horse, and asks him to be on the look-out for one that will fit his requirements.
    - Woodward, L. M., 27 October 1859., 3 pages. XCy of ads. (Box-folder 6:6)
      L. M. Woodward, Western Lunatic Asylum, [Staunton, Virginia], to Na[thaniel Burwell], n.p. Mention of the "Harpers Ferry tragedy"; W[illia]m Baylor is on a "bridal tour" at Niagara Falls; Dr. Echelberger and Sue Baylor were married in the Lutheran Church; also, Mr. Funkhouser and Miss Scott were married, and both couples are also visiting Niagara Falls; comments that "even old Bachellors Would like to get married"; gives news of death of servant Sally.
  - Miscellaneous., 2 items. (Box-folder 6:7)
  Series 9: Manuscript Volumes and Miscellany.
- Manuscript Volumes, and Miscellany, 1919-1973, n.d., 15 items. (Box 7-9)
  Contains manuscript volumes, scrapbooks, journals and awards.
  - Daily Journal of Jay W. Johns, 1919., 1 item. (Box-folder 7:1)
  - Memorandum books and calendar, 1938-1945, 1968., 5 items. (Box-folder 7:2)
  - Distinguished Service Award of Jay Johns, given by the Civil War Round Table, 1 May 1971., 1 item. (Box-folder 7:3)
  - Resolution that Jay W. Johns be elected as an Honorary Member of the Board of Directors of VEPCO, 17 December 1971., 1 item. (Box-folder 7:4)
  - Certificate of membership in the President's Council conferred on Jay W. Johns "in recognition of his able counsel, advocacy, and financial support of the College of William and Mary in Virginia," 1973., 1 item. (Box-folder 7:5)
  - Stock Certificate book of the Atlas Fuel Company., 1 item. (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook containing items relating to the James Monroe Bust Unveiling Ceremony and Ash Lawn., 1 item. (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook containing items relating to James Monroe., 1 item. (Box 8)
  - Engraving plate of the Stonewall Jackson Memorial depicting an equestrian statue of Thomas Jonathan "Stonewall" Jackson., 1 item. (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook containing items relating to James Monroe., 1 item. (Box 9)
  - Scrapbook containing items relating to Ash Lawn., 1 item. (Box 9)
  Series 10: Oversized Items
- Oversized Items, 1792-1979, n.d. (Box-folder Oversize:1-8)
  - Personal Papers: Diplomas and certificates, 1899-1935., 13 items. (Box-folder Oversize:1)
    - Diplomas and Certificates of Jay Winston Johns, 1934-1956., 5 items. (Box-folder Oversize:1)
      - Commonwealth of Virginia - 29th, 1934., 1 item. (Box-folder Oversize:1)
      - Annual convention of the National Rivers and Harbors Congress, 1935., 1 item. (Box-folder Oversize:1)
      - Annual Convention of the Atlantic Deeper Waterways Association (Delegate representative, Virginia), 1935., 1 item. (Box-folder Oversize:1)
      - National Conference on State Park, 1935., 1 item. (Box-folder Oversize:1)
      - House Resolution No. 43, 1956., 1 item. (Box-folder Oversize:1)
    - Diplomas and Certificates of Helen Elizabeth Lambert, 1899., 1 item. (Box-folder Oversize:1)
      Saint Joseph Academy.
    - Diplomas and Certificates of John Lambert Molyneaux, 1922-1926., 2 items. (Box-folder Oversize:1)
      - St. James School 8th Grade, 1922., 1 item. (Box-folder Oversize:1)
      - Bridgeville High School 1926., 1 item. (Box-folder Oversize:1)
    - Diplomas and Certificates of Therese Denise Molyneaux, 1916-1929., 5 items. (Box-folder Oversize:1)
      - Seton Hill School Grammar School, 1916., 1 item. (Box-folder Oversize:1)
      - Saint Joseph Academy High School, 1920., 1 item. (Box-folder Oversize:1)
      - B.A. Seton Hill College, 1924., 1 item. (Box-folder Oversize:1)
      - Diplome de Francais University De Dijon, 1926., 1 item. (Box-folder Oversize:1)
      - M.A. Columbia University, 1929., 1 item. (Box-folder Oversize:1)
  - Lee-Jackson, Inc., 7 items. (Box-folder Oversize:2)
    Pst of U.S. Military Academy diploma of Thomas Jonathan Jackson; Pst of Sketch and site of the Battle of Port Republic, Virginia; Blueprint of Jackson Homestead; Jackson's Mill, West Virginia; Miscellaneous Virginians.
  - Ash Lawn, 1822-1979., 24 items. (Box-folder Oversize:3-5)
    - Photographs, 1822, n.d., 6 items. Photographs. (Box-folder Oversize:3)
      Photographs include the following:
      Slave quarters at Ash Lawn
      Views of the house
      Tricia Nixon and Jay Johns at Ash Lawn
      Print for a magazine article on Ash Lawn
    - Newspaper, Pennsylvania Intelligencer, 30 August 1822., 1 item. (Box-folder Oversize:3)
    - Plat of Ash Lawn, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder Oversize:3)
    - Drawings for Carriage House. (Box-folder Oversize:3)
    - Blueline drawings of Ash Lawn by student of K. Edward Lay, School of Architecture, University of Virginia, Fall semester, 1979., 9 items. Copyrighted. (Box-folder Oversize:4)
    - Set of plans for replica of Oak Hill at Ash Lawn by Edward Campbell, 1933., 6 items. (Box-folder Oversize:5)
  - Manuscript Collection, 14 August 1792., 1 item. Pst of DS. (Box-folder Oversize:6)
    Land patent signed by Henry Lee, Governor of Virginia.
  - Photograph of Mary Custis Lee., 1 items. Photograph. (Box-folder Oversize:7)
  - Reproduction from a photograph from the life of "Stonewall" [Thomas Jonathan] Jackson with a manuscript fragment attached bearing his signature, 1864., 1 item. (Box-folder Oversize:8)
    Printed at bottom: "Entered according to act of Congress A.D. 1864 by C. B. Richardson in the clerks office of the district court of the United States for the southern district of New York."